So how does sending HTTP requests work in react applications typically
yleyse ya, akran taleplerine gndermek, genellikle yeniden hareket uygulamalarnda alr.
and I'm saying typically because if you're creating a multi-page react application, there actually isn't
Ve ben genellikle sylyorum nk ok sayfal bir yeniden uygulama uygulamas oluturuyorsanz bunun iin zel
anything special to it.
bir ey deildir.
You probably have your application, your page where you submit a form and that sends a request to your
Bavurunuzu muhtemelen sayfanz form gnderdiiniz bavurudunuz ve srtnza bir istek gnderir ve oradaki
backend and you get back a new html page with potentially new react code in there.
yeni yeniden ileme kodu ile birlikte yeni bir ya ekibi sayfas dndrrsnz.
You don't have a single page application,
Tek bir sayfa bavurunuz yok.
you don't have a strong decoupling going on.
Gl ayrlma yapmaya devam etmiyorsun.
If you have such a single page application, you have a strong differentiation between your frontend,
veriyor ve sunucularn hala zaman zaman iletiim kurmalar gerekiyor ancak H dei tokuuyla iletiim kurmuyorlar.
your react app and your backend though. The react app and the servers still need to communicate from time
Byle tek bir sayfa uygulamanz varsa, n uunuz ile tepki EP'niz ve srtnz arasnda gl bir ayrma
to time but they don't communicate by exchanging html pages.
sahipsiniz, ancak yine de tepki E. e-posta sayfalar.
So if a react app sends a request to a server,
Bu yzden ar tepki bir sunucuya bir istek gnderir.
you don't get back a new html page instead you can back some json data typically or you send
Geri dnemezsiniz ve G posta sayfas yandasnz, bunun yerine baz Jason verilerini normalde geri alabilir veya
some json data to the server
sunucuya baz Jason verilerini gnderirsiniz.
if you want to create some resources on the server for example. This is how that works, you have that
Sunucuda baz kaynaklar yaratmak isterseniz, rnein bunun nasl iledii
decoupling and your server
bu ayrtrma ve sunucunuzdur.
therefore typically is a RESTful API, just exposing some API endpoints to which you can send requests
tek bana veri almak veya almak iin istek gnderebileceiniz baz API u noktalarn ortaya karmaktadr.
to get or send data from your standalone react application. This is the approach
Dolaysyla, genellikle, dinlendirici bir API'dir ve yalnzca, yaklamnzdaki uygulamaya tepki verdiiniz
I will show you in this module and I will show you how to do that.
Bu Marchal'da size gstereceim ve size nasl yaplacan gstereceim.